Baran Topaloğlu

Mechanical Engineer

Dedicated and passionate young engineer with experience in aerodynamic design and the automotive industry. He made his theses on CAD design and CFD engineering. Able to search and apply different methods to improve the user experience for clients, employees, and administration.

EXPERIENCE

APRO Alüminyum, Adana / Turkey- Project Engineering Intern

May 2021 - June 2021

- Supported the chief engineer with monitoring and analyzing distribution, optimizing overall efficiency, and commentate feedback.
- Implementation and control of the company's quality standards.

ZF LEMFÖRDER, Izmir / Turkey- Mechanical Engineering Intern

June 2018 - July 2018

 Assisted mechanical engineer with technical drawing drafts, 3D rendering, and presenting the final results.

Cukurova University, Adana / Turkey- University Project

September 2016 - November 2017

- Design, analysis, and production of electric vehicle in "Çukurova Electromobile Team" (http://cukurovaelektromobil.com/)
- Tubitak Efficiency Challenge 1st place winner (2017)
- Shell Eco-Marathon Turkey 1st place winner (2017)
- Shell Eco-Marathon Europe 7th place (2017)

AIESEC (Association Internationale des Étudiants en Sciences Économiques et Commerciales), Kyiv / Ukraine – English Teacher

June 2016 - August 2016

 Volunteer language tutoring and child counseling for 8-14 age children in summer camp. (Irpin/Kyiv)

EDUCATION

Anadolu University, Eskişehir / Turkey - Photography and Videography

September 2020 - June 2022

Cukurova University, Adana / Turkey - Mechanical Engineering B.Sc.

September 2015 - June 2021

Theses:

- The aerodynamic design of an automobile.
- CFD analysis of low Reynolds number airfoils for Mars exploration.
- Testing and analyze load/stress factors at elevated temperatures for different materials with Abaqus CAE.

Activ Lernen, Cologne / Germany - German Language School

August 2018 - September 2018

TAKEM (Turkish German Cultural Education Center), Adana / Turkey – German Language School



March 2016 - June 2016

Email baran.topaloglu97@gmail.com

LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/barantopaloğlu-1474261a5

Address

Damar Arikoglu blvd. Nu:24 Unlu Er apt. 3/6 01170 Cukurova/ADANA

Phone

+905309448909

Date and Place of Birth

14.07.1997 Adana / Turkey

SKILLS

CATIA V5

$\star\star\star\star$

Ansys

$\star\star\star\star$

AutoCAD

MS Office

$\star\star\star\star\star$

C++, Phyton

$\star\star\star\star\star$

LANGUAGES

Turkish.....Native

English......Business Fluent

German.....Pre-Intermediate

HOBBIES

Classic car restoration, Photography, Electric guitar, Drum, Watercolor, Hiking, Camping, Travel